Guide to the Hugh Heclo government policy collection, 1901-1991
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Hugh Heclo government policy collection
1901-1991
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Heclo, Hugh
C0074
14 linear feet (29 boxes)
Research materials relating to the executive branch of the United States federal government. Several presidential administrations beginning with the 1932 Roosevelt Administration are represented. Materials include documents pertaining to cabinet posts and functions, federal bureaus, foreign and domestic policy.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Hugh Heclo in 2005.
Biographical Information
Born in Marion Ohio on March 10, 1943 Hugh Heclo is a recognized expert on American democratic institutions as well as the international development of modern welfare states. He has received national awards for his books including Comparative Public Policy; A Government of Strangers: Executive Politics in Washington; and Modern Social Politics in Britain and Sweden. Professor Heclo is an elected member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and the recipient of a Guggenheim Fellowship, and he has served in the White House and as a senior fellow at The Brookings Institution. He chaired the Ford Foundation research advisory committee, which published The Common Good: Social Welfare and the American Future, and is co-author of the 1998 Urban Institute volume, The Government We Deserve. Hugh Heclo is senior editor and contributor to the 2003 volume, Religion Returns to the Public Square: Faith and Policy in America and a member of the Scholars Council advising the Librarian of Congress. Also in 2003, he wrote Ronald Reagan and the American Public Philosophy, chapter one in The Reagan Presidency and the chapter, The Political Ethos of George W. Bush, in The George W. Bush Presidency: An Early Assessment. In 2002 he received the American Political Science Association's John Gaus Award honoring exemplary scholarship in the joint tradition of political science and public administration. Each year, Heclo teaches introductory courses on Democracy and on American Government, and he leads interdisciplinary senior seminars on the Philosophy of History and on Religion and Politics in America.
Scope and Content
Research materials relating to the executive branch of the United States federal government. Several presidential administrations beginning with the 1932 Roosevelt Administration are represented. Materials include documents pertaining to cabinet posts and functions, federal bureaus, foreign and domestic policy.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically by folder title and subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds other political collections, particularly on Northern Virginia politics and government.
Index Terms
Persons:
Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.
Corporate Names:
United States. Bureau of Budget.; United States. President's Advisory Committee on Government Organization.
Geographical Names:
United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.
Contents List
- Hugh Heclo government policy collection
  - Doctrines 9/26/79 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Doctrines of Presidential Management by Michael McGeary for meeting of Panel on Presidential Management, National Academy of Public Administration
  - Sources (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hoover I (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Includes: the First Hoover Commission and the Managerial Presidency by Peri E. Arnold, Journal of Politics, 2/76; handwritten notes on "The Commission on Org of the Exec Br. of the Gov " Concluding Report"" May 1949
  - Hoover II (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Includes a paper; "Administrative Literature and the Second Hoover Commission Reports" by James W. Fesler, Yale University, APSR 3/57
  - Temple U. and Corson 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes a paper; " Temple University Survey of Federal Reorganization, Volume 1"
  - PACGO Records BDEL, NARS (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Finding Aid to NARS files titled; "Records of the President's Advisory Committee on Government Organization 1953-1961 and hand-written notes
  - PACGO - OEM and First See (Box 1, Folder 7)
    hand written notes on Office of Executive management
  - PAGCO 11/19/52 - 4/9/54 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Includes copies of government papers specifically the final recommendations of The President's Advisory Committee on Government Organization (PAGCO)
  - PACGO General Organization, members,Reports 1/14/61 - 1/17/61 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Includes final summaries of PACGO accomplishments
  - PACGO - Interview with members 7/10/80 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Interview of Don K. Price by McGeary
  - PACGO 1961 and Termination 2/10/61 - 5/17/61 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Origin and Development of FEB's [Federal Executive Boards] 4/5/61 - 11/10/61 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    includes 15 memos or summaries of memos leading up to the establishment of FEB's and a undated summary of the development of FEB's
  - President's Price Task Force on Government Organization 10/29/80 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    notes on interview with Don K. Price regarding task force on reorganization in 1964
  - Ash Council Memo's on EOP {Executive Office of the President) 8/20/69 - 1/20/70 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ash Council Memos on Super Depts. 5/12/70 and 11/19/70 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Memos from the Ash Council (Roy L. Ash) to the President, recommending 3 new Departments: Department of Human resources, Department of Community Development, and Department of Economic Growth and Productivity
  - (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - General [documents re: reorganization of Fed'l Government] 11/10/70 - 1/17/73 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Other Ash Council Memos: NOAA, EPA, etc 1/16/70 - 8/17/70 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    includes memo on Organization for Foreign Economic Affairs
  - White House (Box 1, Folder 18)
    includes Executive Branch estimates of appropriations from 1901 to 1911 and a list of White House/Executive Branch personnel and salaries
  - Effecting Reorg. Plan #2, 1970 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    a discussion of Nixon's "failure" to implement a reorganization
  - Presy [Presidency] 2/10/08 - 10/4/25 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    contains documents regarding Theodore Roosevelt
  - PCY course 1/15/45 - 3/79 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    notes and documents to support a course on the President
  - Correspondence and Memos [regarding organization of Executive Branch] 11/19/52 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Article[s] 7/10/79 - 7/27/80 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    news clippings regarding the office of the President
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 5)
    includes paper written by Herman M. Somers, "Coordinating the Federal Executive
  - Interview[s] (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Transcripts of interviews of Luther Gulick, Bryce Harlow, Thomas Cronin, Clifford, Burns, and Neustadt'
  - The Office of Management and Budget That Almost Wasn't: How the Bureau of the Budget Fought to Remain BOB September 1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Prepared for Annual Meeting of APSA by Larry Berman
  - The President's Role in Administrative Management, Harvard University Feb 27, 1946 2/27/46 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Research Report No. 3: Organizational Trends in the Executive Office of the President 2/6/80 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    by Hugh Heclo
  - Our Country and Its Resources [The President - The Executive] 1918 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    by Albert A. Hopkins
  - The Truman Presidency by Elmer E. Cornwell, Jr. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Staff Work for the President and the Executive Branch 8/20/54 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    memorandum from The Assistant to The President to all Departments, Agencies and White House Staff
  - Profiles Mr. President (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Discussion of Harry Truman's presidency
  - Reorganizing The Presidency in 1961: A Preview of the Issues September 1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    by Richard E. Meustadt for Annual meeting of APSA
  - Oral History Interview with David E, Rell 8/20/68, 8/12/68, and 10/16/68 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Mr. Bell held several positions in the Truman administration
  - Oral History Interview with Dr. Harold Seidman 7/29/70 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Oral History Interview James L. Sundquist 7/15/63 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    worked in BOB during Truman presidency
  - Oral History Interview Frederick J. Lawton 6/1763 and 7/9/63 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Oral History Interview with Roger W. Jones 8/14/69 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    worked in BOB during the Truman
  - Oral History Interview Frank Pace, Jr. 1/17/72 - 6/26/72 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Secretary of the Army 1950- 1953
  - Administrative Correspondence 4/1942 - 11/13/42 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Memorandum regarding Mr. Truman's decision to create a 'Administrative Secretary position
  - DAM 1943 9/16/43 - 12/27/43 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Division of Administrative Management(Executive Office)structure, mission and personnel
  - DAM 1944 1/17/44 - 12/1944 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Division of Administrative Management (Executive Office) structure, mission and personnel
  - 1944 Self Appraisal 4/14/44 - 9/1/44 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Bureau of Budget self appraisal and recommendations for improvement
  - GOP Org Project 6/1945 - 11/1/45 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    organization of the President's Executive Office
  - DAM 1945 - 1948 5/25/45 - May 1948 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Division of Administrative Management, Bureau of Budget includes list of accomplishments
  - 1949 Reorganization Plan 2/249 - 7/21/49 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1950 Budgeting and Accounting Procedure Act 7/11/50 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hoover I 1947 - 4/1950 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - DAM 1949 - 1952 1/10/49 - 2/19/51 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Division of Administrative Management
  - Truman White House 1/1946 - 11/4/52 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Origins of President's management improvement program as response to over I - 1949 2/5/49 - 12/13/49 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Improvement 1949 - 1952 6/12/50 - 12/1952 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    President's Committee on Management Improvement
  - president's Management Improvement Program 1949 - 1952 2/1/50 - 12/52 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - OMO (Office of Management and Organization)1952 6/5/52 - 11/24/52 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Office of Management and Organization - reorganization within the Bureau of Budget
  - OMO: 1952 - 1960 8/1/55 - 1/9/61 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Bureau of Budget
  - President's Management Improvement Fund 1953 9/3/53 - 12/31//54 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1959 Self - Study 1/30/59 - 6/2/60 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Self study of Bureau of Budget and proposal to ask agencies to do management improvement studies
  - Rappaport Study, 1956 2/17/56 - 5/22/56 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Survey of Organization and Staffing of the Bureau of the Budget (includes 29 specific recommendations.
  - Management Appraisal Efforts, 1955 - 1961 4/12/61 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    only 1 document: Management Services Program Basic File
  - OEM: 1967 - 1970 5/12/69 - 6/30/69 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    only 2 documents President Nixon's remarks on the 30th Birthday of the Bureau of Budget and suggested reply to press inquiry on a proposed Congressional investigation of BoB
  - OMB Management Systems 1970 3/31/73 - 4/17/.78 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Carter Administration - President's Reorg Project 1977 - 1980 4/1977 - 1/22/80 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Statistical Standards (CSB) 7/10/39 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Central Statistics Board
  - [BOB Field Offices 9/15/42 - 1/27/58 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - GOP, Creation 1939 - 1945 1/23/40 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    contains information on appropriations for the Office of the president 1914 - 1940
  - Legislative Reference 12/17/79 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fiscal Div[ision] 5/7/40 - 7/1/54 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Office of Financial Management, 1956 - 1967 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - NRPB [National Resource Planning Board] 1/19/40 - 4/14/80 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - NSRB [National Security Resources Board] 10/25/49 - 7/30/80 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - NSC 1947 - 1952 [National Security Council] 2/15/48 - 5/18/80 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - CEA [Council of Economic Advisers] 2/8/46 - 10/17/46 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Office of Government Reports 1/26/40 - 5/27/40 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Council of Personnel Administration 6/7/33 - 2/14/44 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - LBJ Papers (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Hand written notes on Louis B'low
  - General Info; Lists of Series - Title 1973 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    contents of National Archives and Records holdings on the Bureau of Budget
  - Misc BOB Series (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - R.G. Series 21.1 General Subject files: 1921 - 1939 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - R.G. Series 21.6 Gen. Admin. of Federal 1921 - 1940 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - R.G. 51, Series 39.10 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - R.G. 51, Series 39.19 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - R.G. 51, Series 39.27 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - R.G. 51, Series 39.29 Admin of BOB 1939 - 1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - R.G. 51, Series 39.32, DAM's Government Organization Branch 1939 - 1952 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Series 39.35, DAM Numerical Subject Files (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Series 41.3, War Records Section (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Series 47.3, Office of Dir. Recover, 1947 - 1952 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Series 52.1, General Records, 1952 - 1960 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Series 52.2, Admin of BOB, 1952 0- 1960 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Series 52.6, DMO's Government Organization Branch 1952 - 1960 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - FDR 7/1979 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    hand written notes and NARS index to historical documents stored at the Franklin D. Roosevelt Library
  - HST [Harry S Truman] 1/1979 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    hand written notes and NARS index to historical documents stored at the Truman Library
  - DDE Dwight D. Eisenhower 5/1977 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    hand written notes and NARS index to historical documents stored at the Dwight D. Eisenhower Library
  - DDEL - PACGO (Box 6, Folder 20)
    hand written notes on material from Dwight D. Eisenhower Library regarding the President's Advisory Committee on Government Organization
  - DDEL - Notes on a, DES Files (Box 6, Folder 21)
    notes regarding from contents some boxes in DDEL
  - JFK (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Notes on how information is organized in John Fitzgerald Kennedy Library and what is relevant to 1961 transition and organization of JFK White House
  - LBJ [Lyndon Baines Johnson] Notes (Box 6, Folder 23)
    hand written notes from LBJ Library Files as well as a memo regarding the files relevant to study
  - LBJ 1977 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    printed list of historical documents in LBJ library
  - David E. Bell 8/1972 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Hand written notes and printed transcript of Oral History Interview with David E. Bell from Truman library
  - Fesler, James W. 11/8/79 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    memo concerning Louis Bronlow and Charles Merriam
  - Frederick M. Davenport (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Eisenhower Administration Oral Interviews 6/25/80 - 7/31/80 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Maxwell Rabb, Ann Whitman, Bradley Patterson, Dillion Anderson, Andrew Goodpastor Robert Bowie, Milton S. Eisenhower
  - DAM - 1942 9/24/42 - 12/15/42 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - DAM - 1940 5/23/40 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - DAM 1942 9/4/40 - 6/27/41 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    planning for administrative units In Federal Agencies
  - Department AM Staffs 9/24/40 - 5/10/46 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    proposal to establish administrative management units in all Federal executive agencies
  - War Agencies 5/25/40 - 6/17/50 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - War History Project 8/1944 - 12/26/1944 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - DAM, PAS & PACH 1/30/34 - 1948 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Public Administration Service and Public Administration Clearing House
  - Organization of Administration Research 2/1939 - 2/1951 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    includes a monograph; "A Review of Organization and Methods Work in the Federal Government by Joseph D. Cooper
  - DAM - Early Recruiting 4/30/43 - 11/4/43 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - BOB 1921 - 1933 12/5/30 - 4/14/33 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - BOB Organization 1933 - 1938 12/1934 - 7/1/38 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - BOB General Organization 1939 -45 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - BOB General Organization 1945 -52 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - BOB General Organization 1953 - 1960 10/1/53 - 1/10/61 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - BOB General Organization 1961 - 1968 7/22/65 - 10/1969 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - BOB General Organization 1969 - 76 8/1970 - 11/1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - FDR and EOP 7/28/80 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - DAM Creation 1939 4/3/39 - 8/2/39 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - BOB: Functions and Organization 10/23/42 - 11/1978 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Organization Charts 1921 - 1939 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Organization Charts 1939 - 1952 (DAM) (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Org Charts 1952 - 1967 (OMO) 1/1953 - 10/1/65 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - ORG Charts 1967 -70 (OEM) 4/6/70 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    only 1 chart
  - Org Charts 1970 on (OMB) 4/16/73 - 9/28/73 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    2 charts
  - DAM 10/30/70 - 4/22/80 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    2 monographs: Options for Organizing the Administrative Management Function in the Executive Office of the President, and The President and Administrative Management
  - BOB OFfice Memos (Box 7, Folder 27)
    hand written notes
  - BOB Staff Orientation Manual 1962 6/1962 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Executive Office of the President, Bureau of Budget
  - Smith 4/15/39 - 6/19/46 8/24/398/6/46 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Harold D(ewey) Smith was director of Federal budget from 4/15/39 to 6/19/46; Notes on Financial Administration (under Smith's direction) in the Michigan State Government 2/1938
  - Pace 2/1/49 - 4/12/50 3/12/49 - 1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Pace was director of budget
  - Dodge 1/22/53 - 4/15/54 1/18/54 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Director of Bureau of Budget
  - Stans 3/18/58 - 1/20/61 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bureau of Budget - Appropriation Hearings 1924 - 1933 12/11/24 - 1/13/32 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - BOB Appropriations 1934 - 1938 12/14/33 - 1/27/37 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - BOB Appropriations 1939 5/21/37 - 4/28/39 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - BOB Appropriations 1940 6/21/39 - 10/13/39 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - BOB Appropriations [ETZ] 1941 11/30/39 - /10/40 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - BOB Appropriations [ETZ] 1942 11/6/40 - 12/20/41 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - BOB Appropriations [ETZ] 1943 11/4/41 - 11/25/41 (Box 8, Folder 1943)
  - BOB [EPZ]Appropriations 1944 7/22/42 - 1/26/44 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - BOB Appropriations [Etz] 1945 12/13/43 - 11/20/44 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - BOB Appropriations 1946 11/18/44 - 3/31/45 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - BOB Appropriations 1947 12/12/45 - 2/5/46 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - BOB Appropriations 1948 11/25/46 - 4/30/47 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - BOB Appropriations 1949 1/19/48 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - BOB Appropriations [Etz] 1950 10/5/48 - 2/10/50 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - BOB Appropriations [Etz] 1951 2/23/50 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - BOB Appropriations [Etz] 1952 4/5/51 - 3/21/52 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - BOB Appropriations [Etz] 1953 - 56 3/18/53 - 4/12/54 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - BOB Appropriations [Etz] 1957 - 60 5/16/56 - 3/16/57 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - BOB Appropriations 1961 - 64 3/6/61 - 4/9/63 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - BOB Staffing & Budget Summaries 1921 - 1980 5/1/59 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    in addition to the one dated copy, the file consists of undated hand written material
  - BOB Tel Directory 10/1945 - 4/1965 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Report of the President's Committee [on Administrative Management 1/8/37 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Administratively Confidential: Briefing Material Executive Office of the President and Domestic Policy Council 12/1/69 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Report of the President's Task Force on Government Reorganization 11/6/64 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Proposed Organization of the Executive Office of the President (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Joint Chiefs of Staff: a System of Coordination in the Executive Branch of the United States Government 11/16/45 - 11/26/45 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Policy Bites 12/1990 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Policy Bites is a bi-monthly letter issued by The Urban Institute -the issue in file examines the budget process
  - OMB in an Era of Perennial Budgeting 1988 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Executive Leadership in Anglo-American Systems 12/1991 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - BOB Memorandum 7/6/39 - 5/9/75 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - BOB, Organizational Division 12/14/41 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Who's Who in the BOB
  - Interview with Leon H. Keyserling 7/14/81 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Keyerserling was on the staff of the Roosevelt Administration and was author and/or staff liaison for several important pieces (e.g. NLRA, NIRA) of "The New Deal" legislation.
  - Trans[ition] 1968 5/1/68 - 1/6/68 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    includes Executive Office internal memorandum regarding Transition
  - LBJ Memorandum 2/17/64 - 8/27/80 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Staff Members Expected to Attend Staff Meetings 5/2/66 - 6/27/66 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    includes memorandum summarizing Executive Office staff meetings
  - LBJ Pres of Adm History 5/3/68 - 12/27/68 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Instrument of Foreign Policy Coordination 4/11/67 - 6/1/67 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Includes staff paper prepared for the President: Instrument of Foreign Policy Coordination,Program Integration and Coordinated Foreign Policy, Organizational Problems and Issues in Foreign Affairs, Leadership To The Secretary of State -- Again, Program Integration as a Means Toward Coordination of Foreign Policy in the Presidential Perspective, Major Problems of Personnel Management in the Department of State
  - LBJ WH 1966 [Lyndon Baines Johnson White House] 12/11/64 - 1/10/69 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Executive Office internal memos
  - LBJ - EGS 3/2/64 - 11/4/68 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Internal memos between President Johnson and his advisors
  - LBJ - BOB 12/30/65 - 11/9/67 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Memo's of Instruction, request for BOB staff studies and memo regarding "news leak"
  - LBJ - Reorganization 11/22/65 - 8/27/68 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - LBJ - Intelligence [Political and Public Relations] 6/3/64 - 9/12/68 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - LBJ Activities, Schedules 11/23/63 - 12/3/68 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    includes notes of advice to LBJ from President Eisenhower(11/23/63)
  - Cabinet 1/21/66 - 11/6/68 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - LBJ Personnel 1/22/66 - -5/6/68 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - LBJ - Transition 10/28/68 - 1/10/69 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - LBJ WH Administration 5/20/64 - 5/16/68 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Request for Reproduction of Documents 1 of 5 8/19/80 - 8/22/80 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - [The Bureau of Budget During the Administration of President Lyndon B. Johnson] (Box 12, Folder 1A)
  - Request for Reproduction of Documents 2 of 5 8/20/80 - 8/22/80 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - [LBJ Government Reorganization] 3/8/65 - 3/9/67 (Box 12, Folder 2A)
  - LBJ Meetings 9/25/65 - 1/30/68 (Box 12, Folder 2 B)
    Includes summary of a 10/13/65 meeting between LBJ and Eisenhower on a variety of topics and an example of staff work.
  - Request for Reproduction of Documents 3 of 5 8/18/80 - 8/21/80 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Organization and Management of the Executive Office of the President 11/24/63 - 12/16/67 (Box 12, Folder 3 A)
  - Federal Government Reorganization 11/12/66 - 5/17/68 (Box 12, Folder 3 B)
  - Cabinet and Staff Meetings 1/10/65 - 1/24/67 (Box 12, Folder 3 C)
  - JATF: Reducing Federal Grant In-Aid Processing Time 7/26/67 - 5/7/68 (Box 12, Folder 3 D)
  - Cost Reduction 6/10/65 - 6/18/68 (Box 12, Folder 3 E)
  - Civil Rights 12/28/64 - 8/12/66 (Box 12, Folder 3 F)
  - Request for Reproduction of Document 4 of 5 8/18/80 - 10/19/80 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Office Space in EOB 4/3/64 - 2/26/68 (Box 12, Folder 4 A)
  - Control of Presidential/Staff Papers 7/23/66 - 1/27/67 (Box 12, Folder 4 B)
  - Staff meeting notes - Viet Nam 1/30/67 - 2/1967 (Box 12, Folder 4 C)
  - Memos of Support for Viet Nam 9/30/66 - 12/3/66 (Box 12, Folder 4 D)